Based on the incredible true story.
The Duchess is a drama, history, romance film directed by Saul Dibb.
A chronicle of the life of 18th century aristocrat Georgiana, Duchess of
Devonshire, who was reviled for her extravagant political and personal life.
Georgiana Cavendish, Duchess of Devonshire, played by Keira Knightley.
Duke of Devonshire, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Lady Spencer, played by Charlotte Rampling.
Charles Grey, played by Dominic Cooper.
Bess Foster, played by Hayley Atwell.
Charles Fox, played by Simon McBurney.
The Duchess is a 2008 historical drama film directed by Saul Dibb, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jeffrey Hatcher and Anders Thomas Jensen, based on the 1998
book Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire by Amanda Foreman, about the late 18th-century English aristocrat Georgiana Cavendish, Duchess of Devonshire.
She was a distant relation of Diana, Princess of Wales, where the quote "There were
three people in her marriage" in the promotional poster comes from.
The Duchess was the older sister of Lady Diana's
great-great-great-grandfather, George Spencer, 2nd Earl Spencer.
The Duchess was released on 5 September 2008 in the United Kingdom.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
It won the Best Costume Design and was nominated for Best
Art Direction at the 81st Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of adultery, infidelity, london,
england, husband wife relationship, politics.
The tone is emotional.